ILGWU Auditing Department Records 5780/192 MF
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Auditing Department Records
1971-1976
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/192 MF
4.56 cubic feet
41 microfilm reels
Records (documents), microfilm.
8679836
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, June 26, 2019
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, June 26, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
The ILGWU Auditing Department was organized in October 1914, under the direction of B.M. Rabinovitch. It was charged with auditing the local unions, joint boards, district councils and departments, and the general office of the ILGWU. The Department presented these reports to the General Executive Board and to the ILGWU's International conventions.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780/079: ILGWU Local 62 Managers' Correspondence 5780/102 P: ILGWU Justice Photographs 5780/192 PUBS: ILGWU Auditing Department Publications
Women's clothing industry--United States; Clothing workers--Labor unions--United States; Textile workers--United States; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Auditing Dept
8679836
- ILGWU - Finance Cancelled Payroll Checks -- Jan. 1971-May 1971 (Reel 1)
- May 1971-August 1971 (Reel 2)
- August 1971-Dec. 1971 (Reel 3)
- December 1971 (Reel 4)
- Jan. 1972-March 1972 (Reel 5)
- March 1972-July 1972 (Reel 6)
- Aug. 1972-Nov. 1972 (Reel 7)
- Nov. 1972-Dec. 1972 (Reel 8)
- Jan. 1973-March 1972 (Reel 9)
- April 1973-July 1973 (Reel 10)
- July 1973-Nov. 1973 (Reel 11)
- Nov. 1973-Dec. 1973 (Reel 12)
- Jan. 1974-March 1974 (Reel 13)
- March 1974-July 1974 (Reel 14)
- Aug. 1974-Dec. 1974 (Reel 15)
- December 1974 (Reel 16)
- Jan. 1975-April 1975 (Reel 17)
- April 1975-Aug. 1975 (Reel 18)
- Aug. 1975-Dec. 1975 (Reel 19)
- ILGWU - (Reel 20)
- ILGWU- (Reel 21)
- ILGWU- (Reel 22)
- ILGWU-Auditing -- L.M. Reports / 1969 Unit #2 to #581 (Reel 23)
- ILGWU -Auditing -- L.M. Reports / 1970 Unit #2 to #469 (Reel 24)
- ILGWU - Auditing -- L.M. Reports / 1971 Unit #2 to #585 (Reel 25)
- ILGWU - Auditing -- L.M. Reports / 1973 Unit #1 to #430 (Reel 26)
- ILGWU - Auditing -- L.M. Reports / 1973 to Unit #1 to #430 (Reel 27)
- ILGWU -- Auditing / Payroll Master Book -- 1970 to 1972 (Reel 28)
- ILGWU -- Auditing / Payroll Master Book -- 1973 to 1976 (Reel 29)
- ILGWU -- Death Benefit Ledger Cards / 1975 #1.00 to #5.99 (Reel 30)
- ILGWU -- Subsidiary Mortgages / 1976 New York to Isaac Sobel (Reel 31)
- ILGWU - Area Expense -- 1975 Ohio-Kentucky -- Ledger Dept. (Reel 32)
- ILGWU - Area Expenses -- 1976 Eastern Reg. to Puerto Rico (Reel 33)
- ILGWU - Auditing -- General Ledger / (Reel 34)
- ILGWU - Auditing -- General Ledger / (Reel 35)
- ILGWU - Auditing -- General Ledger / 1-1-65 to 12-31-76 (Reel 36)
- ILGWU - Auditing -- General Ledger / 4-1-44 to 12-31-64 (Reel 37)
- ILGWU - Auditing -- General Ledger Cards / 1975 #101.01 to #492.00 (Reel 38)
- ILGWU - Auditing -- General Ledger Cards / 1976 #101.01 to #492.00 (Reel 39)
- ILGWU - Auditing -- Area Expenses / (Reel 40)
- ILGWU - Auditing Area Expenses / (Reel 41)